# Yanlong Zhu

930 Benge Drive Apt 301 Arlington, Texas 8179011266 zhuyanlongcs@hotmail.com

#### **Profile**

Master of Engineering in Software Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering in Software Engineering

Strong knowledge of Apache Spark and Hbase

Strong programming skills with Python and Java

Ability to work independently in an unstructured environment and to collaborate with others

One year of internship experience in a data company

## **Education**

**University of Texas at Arlington** 

August 2019 - August 2020

Arlington, Texas

Master of Science in Computer Science **Key Courses:** Artificial Intelligence (A), Algorithm (A), Software Engineering(A)

GPA achieved: 4/4, A

**Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications** 

August 2018 - June 2021

Beijing, Beijing

Master of Engineering in Software Engineering

**Key Courses:** Object-oriented analysis and design(A), intelligence algorithm (A), Data Mining(B+), Data Warehousing and Knowledge Discovery(B+)

Nanjing University of Posts and Telecommunications

August 2014 - July 2018

BEng in Software Engineering

Nanjing, Jiangsu

- **Key Courses:** Programming in C (A+), Cloud computing (A+), Linear Algebra(A+), Data Structure (B+), Algorithm (A), Programming in Java (A+)
- **GPA** achieved: 3.75/5

# Work Experience

#### **HL95**

Data Engineer Beijing, Beijing

October 2018 – March 2019

- Developing Hadoop / Spark / Map Reduce applications on HL95's cloud platform.
- Combining technology, intellectual property, and industry knowledge to deliver datamanaging solutions that help enterprises improve their customers' experiences, develop new revenue streams, and lower the costs of business.

#### YonYou

Algorithm Engineer

, Beijing

March 2019 – August 2019

- Develop data analysis platform based on Spark
- Combining machine learning and industry knowledge to modeling to help enterprises to lower the costs of business.

# Project Experience

#### **Course Projects:**

#### 2018.10-2018.12 Movie search engine based on recommendation algorithm

Supervising and leading teams of programmers in software development

Using Elasticsearch to build a MovieSearch app

Investigating and using simhash algorithm to implement movie recommendations.

### 2018.10-2018.12 An Sign-in System Based on Android Platform

Supervising and leading teams of programmers in software development

Investigating and using dhash algorithm to implement the face verification

Developing Location Check-in using haversine formula

#### 2017.10-2017.12 A Library Management System

The system is based on Qt framework and C/S structure

Designed, Developed the system in C++

# **Professional Skills**

Spark: • • • • ○

Python: • • • ○

Data Mining: • • • • ○ Hbase: • • • ○

Machine Learning: • • • • ○

Java: • • • ○ ○

# Languages

Chinese: Native English: Proficient